Hello !
I would now like us to work...
on a technique called: "tulip twist"
We must insert an index into the balloon this way,
so that we push the balloon knot inside the ballon.
Then, the idea, with the other hand...
is to catch the knot through the balloon skin,
and hold it firmly!
Once the knot is held securely with the other hand,
we must very carefully extirpate the index from the balloon,
with the help of the thumb and the major if necessary,
Be very careful not to do this too bruskly,
otherwise the balloon could burst!
And finally, just twist the balloon,
just like you would while making a classic bubble!
The knot is now stuck...
on the other side of the tulip-twist.
Now, if we want to use the tulip-twist for a flower,
all we would do is insert the petals directly in this fold.
On the other hand, if we wanted to leave use the tulip-twist on its own,
we would have to push back the balloon knot... in this fashion
a little bit inside the tulip-twist,
to lock the knot a bit more securely.
You will see, tulip-twists" are used,
for example to make flowers,
where they go in between petals,
we will soon see that in another lesson.
Also, to make car wheels, for example,
etc, etc, it's a very important technique...
which you must learn to master!
That's it for today.
See you very soon,
for another lesson...
with Môssieur Ballon!